springbot.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy - Springbot

**Springbot**

 **Privacy Policy**

 **Effective Date** : _07/06/18_

Springbot, Inc. (“Springbot”, “we”, “us”, or “our”) recognizes the importance of privacy. We streamline the process of automating, analyzing, and personalizing an eCommerce store’s marketing campaigns through an all-in-one platform and data-driven marketing recommendations (collectively, the “Services”). In this Privacy Policy, we describe how we collect, use, and disclose information that we obtain about visitors (“Visitors”) to our website _www.springbot.com_ and any related subdomains (collectively, the “Site”); users who have registered accounts with us to use our Services (“Customers”); and the end users of our Customers’ eCommerce stores or individuals that Customers may wish to market to using our Services (“End Users”). Our use of “you” refers collectively to Visitors, Customers, and End Users.

By using any of our Services, Visitors and Customers agree that their information, including personal information, will be collected, used, and disclosed as described in this Privacy Policy. Their use of our Services, and any dispute over privacy, is subject to this Privacy Policy and our [_Terms of Use_](https://www.springbot.com/terms-of-use-privacy-policy/), including its applicable limitations on damages and the resolution of disputes. We have no direct relationship with End Users, however, so our Customers are solely responsible for ensuring that they have the appropriate permission for us to collect, use, and disclose information about End Users.

Springbot Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the Federal Trade Commission.

 _Information We Collect_

 _How We Use Information_

 _How We Disclose Information_

 _Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms_

 _Third-Party Analytics_

 _Do Not Track Disclosure_

 _Interest-Based Advertising_

 _Third-Party Collection_

 _Security_

 _Your Choices_

 _Your California Privacy Rights_

 _Children_

 _Contact Us_

 _Changes to this Privacy Policy_

 **Information We Collect**

We collect information about you directly from you, from third parties, and automatically through your interaction with our Services. We may combine information that we collect from these various sources.

  *  ** _Information We Collect Directly from You._** We may collect information about you directly from you. For example, if you create an account with us, we will collect your name, email address, password, and store URL; if you pay for any Services, we will also collect your payment card information and billing address. We will also collect any other information that you provide to us through our Services, such as your name, email address, and the contents of your message if you contact us through our Site.
  *  ** _Information We Collect from Third Parties._** We may collect information about you from third parties. For example, if you are an End User, we will collect information about you from our Customers. We will also collect information about you from social media platforms, data aggregators, and providers of marketing services. Springbot is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties from which it receives information about you. Please see our _Third-Party Collection_ section below for more information.
  *  ** _Information We Collect Automatically._** We automatically collect information about you through your use of our Services, including, without limitation IP address, location, browser type, domain name, the website that led you to our Services, the website to which you go after leaving our Services, the dates and times you access our Services, device ID, and activities within our Services ( _e.g._ , links you click, searches you run, etc.). Please see our _Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms_ section below for more information. In addition, we also automatically collect information about your use of our Services, such as transaction data ( _e.g._ , date and time of purchase, amount of purchase), product data ( _e.g._ , product purchased, category of product purchased), and behavioral data ( _e.g._ , time spent engaging with a particular product).

 **How We Use Information**

We use the information that we collect, including personal information, for the following purposes:

  *  ** _Providing and Improving Our Services._** To provide and maintain our Services; to improve our Services; to develop new features or services; to perform technical operations, such as updating software; and for other customer service and support purposes.
  *  ** _Research and Analytics._** To analyze how you interact with our Services; to monitor and analyze usage and activity trends; and for other research, analytical, and statistical purposes.
  *  ** _Marketing and Communications._** To communicate with Customers about their use of our Services, including to send them updates, respond to their inquiries, and provide them with news and newsletters, special offers, promotions, and other information we think may interest them, and for other informational, marketing, or promotional purposes. Our communications with Customers may include communications via email. Please see our section regarding _Your Choices_ for more information about how to change your communications preferences.
  *  ** _Protecting Rights and Interests._** To protect the safety, rights, property, or security of Springbot, the Services, any third party, or the general public; to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; to prevent or stop activity which Springbot, in its sole discretion, may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, an illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity; to use as evidence in litigation; and to enforce this Privacy Policy or our [_Terms of Use_](https://www.springbot.com/terms-of-use-privacy-policy/).
  *  ** _Legal Compliance._** To comply with applicable legal or regulatory obligations, including as part of a judicial proceeding; to respond to a subpoena, warrant, court order, or other legal process; or as part of an investigation or request from law enforcement or a governmental authority.

 **How We Disclose Information**

We disclose the information that we collect, including personal information, as described to you at the time of collection or as consented by you before disclosure, or as follows:

  *  ** _Affiliates_** ** _._** We may disclose information to current or future affiliates or subsidiaries for research, marketing, and other purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  *  ** _Service Providers_** ** _._** We may disclose information to our vendors, service providers, agents, or others who perform functions on our behalf. For example, we may disclose information to partners in our data co-op to help Customers expand their markets.
  *  ** _Customers_** ** _._** We may disclose information about End Users to our Customers for purposes of providing our Services.
  *  ** _Other Unaffiliated Third Parties._** We may disclose your information to third parties, including so that those third parties may send marketing information to you.
  *  ** _Business Transfers_** ** _._** We may disclose information to another entity in connection with, including during negotiations of, an acquisition or merger, sale or transfer of a business unit or assets, bankruptcy proceeding, or as part of any other similar business transfer.
  *  ** _Protecting Rights and Interests._** We may disclose information to protect the safety, rights, property, or security of Springbot, the Services, any third party, or the general public; to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; to prevent or stop activity which Springbot, in its sole discretion, may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, an illegal, unethical, or legally actionable activity; to use as evidence in litigation; and to enforce this Privacy Policy or our [_Terms of Use_](https://www.springbot.com/terms-of-use-privacy-policy/).
  *  ** _Legal Compliance._** We may disclose information to comply with applicable legal or regulatory obligations, including as part of a judicial proceeding; in response to a subpoena, warrant, court order, or other legal process; or as part of an investigation or request from law enforcement or a government official.
  *  ** _Aggregate and De-Identified Information_** ** _._** We may disclose aggregate, anonymous, or de-identified information for marketing, advertising, research, compliance, or other purposes.

 **Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms**

We or our service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about how you use our Services. We or our service providers may combine this information with other information, including personal information, we collect about you.

 ** _Cookies._** Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to a computer’s hard drive through a web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Services, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities while using our Services. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers provides information about how to prevent a computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify upon receiving a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Users who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Services, but some features may not function.

 ** _Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies._** Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (also referred to as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags) in connection with our Services to, among other things, track user activities, help us manage content, and compile statistics about usage of our Services. We and our service providers also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to you, to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed, and track whether our emails are forwarded.

 **Third-Party Analytics**

We may use third-party analytics companies, such as [_Google Analytics_](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/), to evaluate use of our Services. We or our service providers use these tools to help us understand use of, and to improve, our Services, performance, and user experiences. These entities may use cookies and other tracking technologies, such as web beacons or local storage objects (“LSOs”), to perform their services. To learn more about Google’s privacy practices, please see the [_Google Privacy Policy_](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/); to opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics, you can download the [_Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on_](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

 **Do Not Track Disclosure**

Our Services do not respond to Do Not Track signals. For more information about Do Not Track signals, please click [_here_](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/). You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed in the _Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms_ section above ( _e.g._ , by disabling cookies).

 **Interest-Based Advertising**

We use third parties such as network advertisers to display advertisements on our Services, to assist us in displaying advertisements on third-party services, and to evaluate the success of advertising campaigns. You may opt out of many third-party ad networks, including those operated by members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) and the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”). For more information regarding this practice by NAI members and DAA members, and your choices regarding having this information used by these companies, including how to opt out of third-party ad networks operated by NAI and DAA members, please visit their respective websites: [_www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp_](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp) (NAI) and [_www.aboutads.info/choices_](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) (DAA).

Opting out of one or more NAI member or DAA member networks (many of which will be the same) only means that those members no longer will deliver targeted content or ads to you. It does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content or ads on our Services or other services. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing ( _i.e._ , contextual advertising). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit an opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different computer or change web browsers, your NAI or DAA opt out may no longer be effective.

 **Third-Party Collection**

Our Services may contain links to third-party websites and applications or integrate with services provided by third parties. Any access to and use of such linked websites, applications, or third-party services is not governed by this Privacy Policy but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third parties. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third parties, and we encourage you to read their privacy policies.

 **Transfers to Third Parties.** As described above, we transfer personal information from the EU to third parties. We contractually require third parties to whom we transfer personal information to provide the same level of protections as the Principles. If we transfer personal information to a third party for its own use, individuals may opt-out of this type of transfer by contacting support@springbot.com. Springbot Inc. remains responsible for the personal information we receive and transfer under Privacy Shield.

 **Security**

We have taken steps to help protect the personal information we collect. However, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your devices by, among other things, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess and keeping your log-in and password private.

 **Your Choices**

 ** _Updating or Deleting Personal Information._** Visitors and Customers may correct or delete the personal information that they provide to us by emailing us at [_support@springbot.com_](mailto:support@springbot.com) and describing their request to update or delete their personal information. Please note that we may retain certain information about them as required by law or as permitted by law for legitimate business purposes ( _e.g._ , in accordance with our record retention policies or to enforce our [_Terms of Use_](https://www.springbot.com/terms-of-use-privacy-policy/)). End Users who wish to correct or delete the personal data that we use on behalf of Customers should contact the Customer with which they interact to make such a request.

 ** _Opting out of Email Communications._** We may send periodic promotional or informational emails to Visitors and Customers. Visitors and Customers may opt out of such communications by following the opt-out instructions contained in the email or contacting us at the _Contact Us_ information below. Please note that it may take up to 10 business days for us to process opt-out requests. If Visitors or Customers opt out of receiving marketing emails from us, we may still send them non-promotional emails ( _e.g._ , about their account with us). If you are an End User that receives emails from one of our Customers and you no longer want to be contacted by that Customer, please unsubscribe directly from that Customer’s communication or contact the Customer directly to update your email preferences.

 **Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California resident you may request from us once a year, free of charge, information about the personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request via email to [_support@springbot.com_](mailto:support@springbot.com). In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response.

 **Children**

Our Services are not targeted to children under thirteen (13) years of age, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. If we discover that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will promptly delete such personal information from our systems.

 **Privacy Shield**

Springbot complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States.  Springbot has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit  <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Springbot commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information.  EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Springbot at:

[ _support@springbot.com_](mailto:support@springbot.com) or 404-487-6672

Springbot has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to VeraSafe, an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your complaint to your satisfaction, please contact or visit VeraSafe for more information or to file a complaint.  The services of VeraSafe are provided at no cost to you.

 **Dispute Resolution**

 **Contacting Us, Complaints and Dispute Resolution.** EU individuals who have questions or complaints about how we process their personal information may contact us at [support@springbot.com](mailto:support@springbot.com) or contact our E.U resolution partner [Verasafe](https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/dispute-resolution/submit-dispute/). We will work to resolve your issue as quickly as possible, but in any event no later than 45 days of receipt.

Within the scope of this privacy notice, if a privacy complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through Springbot Inc.’s internal processes, Springbot Inc. has agreed to participate in the [VeraSafe Privacy Shield Dispute Resolution Procedure](https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/dispute-resolution/privacy-shield-dispute-procedure/). Subject to the terms of the [_VeraSafe Privacy Shield Dispute Resolution Procedure,_](https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/dispute-resolution/privacy-shield-dispute-procedure/) VeraSafe will provide appropriate recourse free of charge to you. To file a complaint with VeraSafe under the Privacy Shield Dispute Resolution Procedure, please submit the required information to VeraSafe here:  [_https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/dispute-resolution/submit-dispute/_](https://www.verasafe.com/privacy-services/dispute-resolution/submit-dispute/)

Individuals may also submit complaints through their local Data Protection Authority (DPA). We will work with the Department of Commerce to resolve any complaints forwarded by a DPA.  Finally, if we are unable to resolve any complaints through any of the above methods, an EU individual may invoke binding arbitration in accordance with the Privacy Shield Framework.

 **Contact Us**

If you have questions about the privacy aspects of our Services or for further information about our data privacy policies and practices, please contact us at [_support@springbot.com_](mailto:support@springbot.com) or 404-487-6672.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is current as of the Effective Date set forth above. We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. We will post any changes, including any material changes, to this Privacy Policy on our Site.
